INSPIRED BY TRUE EVENTS
Alpha 09. One hundred yards away
from the target.
Attention.
Prepare for apprehension of subject.
OC for Alpha 09. Ready to go.
Alpha 09 for OC. Copy.
Be careful. Good luck. Over and out.
Police!
Hands on your back. The other one too.
Take him away.
Get up. Head down.
Nico. what is this?
-Police.
-You're under arrest.
Take it easy. Sit down. Relax.
Get off me!
Don't be so rough. I'm walking.
Fucking pigs!
You've got some explaining to do.
Why did they fire at the restaurant.
who were the shooters on the motorbike.
and who ordered the hit?
I don't know anything.
But why would someone shoot up
your restaurant?
How should I know? In my 15 years
nothing like that has ever happened.
-You must have seen something.
-I just do the reception.
You receive. alright.
He must have said something about
what he translates for us. his work here.
-Surely you would know if I was lying.
-That's what I thought about Umut. Semia…
We have nothing.
VETERINARY CLINIC MAASSLUIS
-It's beating so fast. Is that normal?
-Yes.
Is our baby broken?
Rom. a baby heart
beats much faster than ours.
Isn't it weird you're sitting on the table
you use to chop off
rottweilers' balls and stuff?
Christ.
No. I don't think it's weird.
-Are you okay?
-Yeah. it's just a stitch.
-Have you thought of names yet?
-Names?
Yes.
No. not at all. actually.
Was I supposed to?
-I don't get a say anyway.
-You're such a drama queen.
I do have a name in mind.
…the hospital where the victim
has been admitted. The big question is:
Is this yet another drug-related hit?
Mayor Limon just arrived
to visit the family.
Mrs. Limon. how is the girl doing?
I'm seeing the family first.
Please. Mrs. Limon. Do you know
who's behind the attack yet?
Mayor Limon is visiting
the 12-year-old Amaya Graauw.
who was critically injured in the shooting
at a Rotterdam restaurant.
What a nightmare for the parents.
The exact link between the restaurant
and the organized crime network
is being investigated by the police.
The restaurant remains sealed off.
I know this is awful. but I need
to ask you a few questions.
-I'm recording this. okay?
-Of course.
Any idea what happened?
Is anyone angry with you?
Any disagreements?
Sir. we weren't even supposed to be there.
We only went in
because Amaya needed to pee.
How is she?
They keep her in a coma
until the swelling comes down.
The pressure in her brain was too high.
She will never be able to see again.
Roman.
Yes?
I want you to listen for any peculiarities
in our interrogations of the witnesses.
Yeah. okay.
I'm going to question Umut.
see if he can tell me what's going on.
I'll come with you.
I'm coming with you.
That's not allowed.
I just want to listen.
Maybe I'll pick up on something you don't.
Absolutely not.
You said we were going to get them
together. You and me. Didn't you?
You keep your mouth shut.
Come on then.
How long have we known each other. Umut?
Twenty years?
How long have you been mistranslating?
And who for?
I don't know what you're talking about.
What are they paying you?
If I start talking. who do you think
will be next? Me? Semia? The kid?
Do you know what they do
to people who talk to cops?
If you don't talk. then what?
Those guys won't stop unless we stop them.
Talk.
We can protect you.
Make sure nothing happens to you.
Her name is Amaya.
The girl who got injured in the attack.
her name is Amaya.
She's eight years old.
And she'll be blind
for the rest of her life.
You have a kid too. right?
I was about the same age
when I went blind.
The first few weeks are the worst.
You're disoriented.
Your brain doesn't believe
you can't see anymore.
Every day you hope you'll get to see
again. but that just doesn't happen.
You can't do anything anymore.
Okay. Roman.
Here you will learn everything. okay?
Prove you're just as capable
as a sighted kid.
Do you know how hard it is
to not be able to do anything?
Wait. Roman. Bring them together.
That's it.
Press them against each other.
and you'll be able to feel it.
You don't want to know what it's like.
To be trapped inside your own head.
I get that you're scared.
But that doesn't mean
you can't do the right thing.
Do you know The Beatles?
I'm more of a Stones fan. Umut.
Not those Beatles. I mean…
The Uzbek Beatles.
Rotterdam has one of the most secure
ports in the world. you know that.
Anyone who wants to get something
through the port has to work with them.
Those four have been supplying manpower
to various international gangs for years.
Like an employment agency for criminals.
Extractors.
Bargemen. Straddle drivers.
Truck drivers. Muscle.
And in return they get
a percentage of the profits.
-And they've made a lot of profit.
-Who are those Beatles?
I only know one of them.
They call him George Harrison.
Couldn't you have told me sooner.
you fuck?
Why are they beating
each other's brains out?
From what I've heard. John Lennon
jacked a container from McCartney.
-Street value: 100 million euros.
-Fuck!
McCartney found out
and wants the container back.
Or 100 million.
Nico. that McCartney…
The things I hear about him…
The guy is a real psycho.
Fuck you. Umut!
Fuck you!
Finally we have a big breakthrough.
This is a unique opportunity.
All violence leads back to him.
If we take down this McCartney.
we end the war on our streets
and catch the men behind the attack.
And there's more.
His address book contains contacts
from international top cartels.
Through him we can put a stop
to the drug trade in our city
and across all of Western Europe.
From now on he's our top priority.
We don't know who he is.
but we do know how to get to him.
Yaqub Nurmatov.
Half Uzbek. half Dutch.
100 percent dickhead.
And according to Umut he is…
George Harrison.
-How does Umut know him?
-Nurmatov paid Umut for information.
so I think there's a direct line
from Nurmatov to McCartney.
He's a luxury real estate broker.
so he could be the main money launderer
of the fucking bunch.
Okay. arrest and interrogate?
If you want McCartney to disappear
before we begin. sure.
No. I say we plant some RCCs on our friend
and see what rises to the surface.
-Okay. let's do it.
-Good plan.
-I need some caffeine. You too?
-Yeah. sure. Number one.
Hey. earlier you were talking
about RCCs or something.
What is that?
-Sometimes I forget you're not a real cop.
-I wouldn't trust me with a gun.
RCC: Recording Confidential Communication.
We're going to install bugs
in Yaqub's house. his office. his car.
Instead of just tapping his phone.
we'll be able to listen in
to all of his conversations.
Okay. And how long do I have
to wait for those?
Wait?
You're coming with us to plant them.
ROTOWN ESTATES
REAL ESTATE AGENCY
Nico? What should Umut have done?
They threatened him.
He didn't really have a choice.
He should've said no.
Once you say yes and take their money.
there's no getting away from them.
Alright. we're going to set this stuff up.
and then you check
if you can hear everything. okay?
Yo. Let's roll.
We start in his office.
We have to get everyone out
so we can do our thing in peace.
Hey. Roman. Who you gonna call?
But I have a plan to make that happen.
Gas detection. good afternoon.
We've detected a gas leak.
Leave as quickly as possible
before the place blows up.
Hang on. You can't just do this.
Go with my colleague.
he'll explain everything.
Beat it.
We have to be able to listen in anywhere.
-Is this okay. Roman?
-Lovely.
Right. Roman. old coconut. how's that?
All good.
If he farts behind his desk.
we want to hear it.
Tess. one. two. three. Sick motherfuckers.
Perfect.
Yaqub has lunch at restaurant New China
almost every day at noon.
That's when we're going to bug his car.
They're seated.
Bring on that truck.
Subject no longer has a visual.
You can go ahead.
Then we go to his house.
It just so happens Yaqub's wife. Sophie.
has to go to city hall today
to renew her passport.
And that will take a while.
Longer than usual.
HANDYMAN SERVICE
-We're in. Roman. can you hear us?
-Perfectly.
-Tess. one. two.
-Very good. Tess.
-Okay like this?
-Yes. that's good.
A built-in fryer. Nice.
-Can you hear me. Roman?
-Like we're in the same room.
-All good?
-Yep. loud and clear.
And you need it right now?
Sorry. I didn't know. No.
Fuck.
Subject is down the street.
I repeat. she is down the street.
-Goddamn it.
-Arrival within a minute.
-Do something. loser.
-I'll have a look and bring it to school.
-Excuse me. can I ask you something?
-Sorry. what did you say?
I couldn't stop her.
Fifteen seconds. Get out. now.
Fuck! There's no other exit.
-Yes. I'm coming right away.
-Subject is at the door.
-What's going on?
-She's looking for her keys.
Help!
Sam!
-What's happening?
-Sam! Where's my dog? Sam!
My dog is…
Shit. Goddamn it. Help!
My dog Sam ran off. I don't know where…
-Could you help me?
-Let's get out of the street.
-Roman's distracting her.
-A brown Labrador. Can you have a look?
-There's this big street.
-I'll help you.
I think he went over there somewhere.
Is that possible?
They're almost out of sight.
Yes. now. Go. go. go.
-Let's go.
-Fuck.
To Roman. Actor. liar…
In short. a real cop.
Cheers.
-Cheers.
-Well. that was close.
-Right. If she had come in…
-Nice.
-Do we have a new interpreter yet?
So much for the good mood.
Well. that was fun. guys.
Sorry. but we can't ask Umut to translate
the new Uzbek conversations coming in.
No. the judge won't like that.
It won't be easy to find someone.
It's a very small. closed-off community.
Candidates can't be trusted.
or they're scared.
So. Roman. I was thinking…
No. absolutely not.
-You don't even know what I want to ask.
-I'm not asking Meryem.
Why not?
That's… No.
Too much has happened in the past.
Meryem?
Oh well. we all have a past.
If you only knew about Nico's.
-Remember. Nico? The police academy?
-Shut up or I'll kill you.
-All your secrets are safe with me.
-Don't walk away. Nico.
-What was your nickname again?
-I told you to shut up. didn't I?
-Come on.
-I can give something away. right?
-No way.
-Just a little hint.
What kind of animal was it again?
I already told you. I won't do it.
How the fuck did you know it was me?
Your snorting.
You know. I think it'd be best
if you shut that big mouth of yours.
You know what they do
to people who don't cooperate.
They cut off your ears.
throw you off a crane.
I once saw someone pop out an eyeball
with a screwdriver.
That won't happen to you.
there's no point. but still.
It's not like you'd be doing it for free.
I'll give you ten K each time.
Ten fucking K.
You hear?
Just leave me alone.
As you wish. but I'll come back tomorrow.
and every day after.
Hi. honey.
-Hey.
Hey. where were you?
No. don't take your coat off. we're late.
-Late? For what?
-For the class. Rom. Come on.
-Sorry. we have to go. Turn around.
-Sam. come.
Hello. everyone. Thank you for coming.
and welcome to the baby-care class
for people with a visual impairment.
We'll do a lot of talking today.
a lot of learning.
but we'll also get hands-on with diapers
and many other things that have to do
with taking care of a baby.
But first I want to know
what you would like to learn.
Perhaps… Roman. why are you here?
Me?
-How many potatoes?
-A lot.
-A lot?
-How many endives?
-No that many.
-Give him a lot.
-Go crazy.
-It's good for you.
Oh dear. He threw up a little.
-Seriously?
-Yes.
-Here. grab your plate. Yeah?
-Will you give him a bath?
-A bath? Alright.
-I'll help you. Bo.
-Yeah. sure.
It's okay. yeah?
Alright. there we go. And now the hair.
There.
Now he'll smell fresh for 15 minutes
until he poops or pees himself again.
Shit. I forgot the diapers.
Can you hold him?
-Just hold him for a second.
-Yeah. sure.
I'll be right back.
It's okay. it's okay.
Oh. shit. Fuck.
Hey. Bo! Hey!
Bo! Help! Come here!
It's okay. The baby is fine.
I'm so sorry. Bo. Is he okay?
Roman?
I think I just wanted to…
I'm just here to listen.
Maybe I'll learn something new.
Okay. that's fine. And you. Fien?
-Hey.
-Nico.
You okay?
Hey. man.
Can we talk?
Head upstairs.
It's important no one knows you talked.
That everything seems normal.
We're getting you protection.
Just in case.
For now our people will handle it.
otherwise it'll take too long to arrange.
We'll make sure
there's always someone around.
And I'll let the judge know
you helped us out a lot.
POLICE
Sit. Sam.
Good morning. Roman.
Yaqub hasn't shut up.
Thirty conversations have already come in.
30 RECORDINGS
And? Is he an influencer yet?
Something strange happened. This blind guy
was standing in the middle of the street.
He nearly got hit by a scooter.
He had lost his dog.
So I helped him out. He was panicking.
Good thing he was blind.
or he would've fallen for you on the spot.
NOT RELEVANT
TO BE TRANSLATED
And what was twelve minus five again?
I forgot.
-Seven. Dad.
-Very good.
Sweetheart. will you try on
those new golf shoes?
If they fit. I can get rid of the box.
Blue.
I'm going to stand out.
I'll try them on and take them upstairs.
NOT RELEVANT
AWAITING TRANSLATION:
3 RECORDINGS
13 RECORDINGS
Call Meryem.
Hey. sweetie?
There's a phone call for you.
A certain Roman?
Hey. Roman.
Hey. Meryem. We're in trouble.
-With that attack?
-I'm listening to this Uzbek criminal.
But we don't have an interpreter.
So I wanted to ask if you're up
for coming to Rotterdam to translate.
I don't think that's a good idea.
Sorry. I really can't.
-Is that the Roman from the institute?
-Yes.
He works for the police now. and wants me
to help him translate Uzbek in Rotterdam.
-In Rotterdam?
-Yes.
But it's okay. I'm fine right here.
Are you?
Five minutes late.
Where the fuck is that thing?
I'm not exactly the patient type.
Did you know that about me. Roman?
It's not coming. We're not waiting.
I'll take you wherever you want.
But on the way we're visiting a few people
who want to give you a lot of money.
All you have to do is talk a little.
Sounds good. right? Come on.
-Let's go. Sam.
-Hey. Sammie. Hi. boy.
Leave me the fuck alone.
Listen. Roman. You're going to talk.
If you don't. this won't end well.
It really won't. I swear to you.
-Leave me the fuck alone.
-Sammie. hi.
Leave me alone!
Thanks. For coming in the end.
Alright… No matches on the ammunition.
We don't know anything about the shooters.
and the restaurant's books are in order.
We've asked around everywhere
and no one's heard of this McCartney guy.
Or they're all scared.
The mayor and De Geeter are calling
every hour. and I've got nothing for them.
Ah. there's the new Uzbek interpreter.
Oh. did we find someone?
DO NOT PET
-Is she blind too?
-Jesus. Tess. not this again.
Everyone. this is Meryem.
-Hey.
Hello. everyone.
-Welcome.
-Great to have you. Don't you have a dog?
-No. I don't.
-Don't you have a dog. Tess?
No.
I have a goldfish.
-Found your new toys?
-Yes. Cool.
And when I ask for new equipment.
I get denied.
Things always get denied.
until they don't.
The mayor personally
allocated funds for it.
Hey…
Be nice to each other.
Okay. Mey. I'll play it. you translate.
AWAITING TRANSLATION:
13 RECORDINGS
Yeah. I know. But I have to be
at the golf club at three.
What time is it exactly?
It's a quarter to two.
We'll be on time.
No worries.
I told you. They don't have
any good wingers.
Later. when that little one's
all grown up.
I'm going to wake him up every two hours
at night as well. I swear to you.
Yummy.
It's kind of exciting. isn't it? All this.
That guy. Yaqub…
He helps his son with his homework
every day.
and they play soccer in the yard.
Umut says he's this big criminal.
but I don't believe that.
You don't?
He seems like a great guy. A good dad.
For all we know.
we're wasting our time on this Yaqub.
Honestly…
Want to do another clip?
-If you're up to it.
-I am.
What's wrong with those guys?
An eight-year-old girl.
How's this possible?
What isn't clear about "orange"?
Roman. why did you stop?
What's going on?
We have to call Nico.
Alright…
What's so urgent?
Was there an orange car
when Amaya got shot?
I spy with my little eye…
something orange.
-Is it that car?
-That's right.
Mom. come on.
There was.
The attack wasn't aimed at the restaurant.
but at the driver of that car.
-Why were you there?
-I was just buying a newspaper.
I had double-parked my car
and was expecting a ticket.
Not bullets.
Goddamn it. There goes my evening.
Yes. We're home.
Did they finally release you?
Yeah. it took a while.
but it worked out in the end.
It smells interesting in here.
-Well…
-What do you think. Sam?
If you had been home on time.
you could have cooked. like always.
It's okay. I already had pizza
at work with Mey.
Is that your coworker?
It's Meryem from back in the day.
from the institute.
She's helping with the investigation
into those Uzbeks.
What?
She's translating.
until we find a proper interpreter.
Okay.
Nico. cop.
What's up. Nico?
Roman. we turned that car inside out.
Yes. bingo.
-And we found a hidden compartment.
-Double bingo.
The owner. Frank Peeters.
is definitely involved.
Okay. And now what?
We start tapping tonight.
so you can get busy tomorrow.
I'm going to see Umut.
see what he knows about Frank.
You can say it. Nico.
Yeah. yeah. You were right. Jackass.
Okay. thanks. Nico. Bye.
-What was that?
-Nico.
To say I did a fantastic job.
Having a nice snack.
So the attack was intended for Frank.
And what happens to him now?
We're going to wiretap him. Listen in.
And then hopefully either he or Yaqub
will lead us to McCartney.
-And then we take the whole thing down.
-Jesus.
Yeah…
-Hey. doggie.
-What's wrong with him?
-He's throwing up his food.
-Maybe he ate something you made.
No. he's having convulsions
and there's blood coming out of his mouth.
Sam. buddy.
-Did something happen to him?
-No.
Sam. hey.
I'm taking you downstairs. come on.
-Downstairs? Why?
-Come on. sweetie. Come on. baby.
-Caro. hey.
-We have to go downstairs. Sorry. Come.
His stomach is all swollen.
Rom. think. Did he eat something
he shouldn't have?
You're going to talk. alright?
Or this won't end well.
It really won't. I swear to you.
-Leave me the fuck alone.
-Sammie. hi.
Leave me alone!
No. not that I know of.
I have to operate on him.
I need your help. okay?
-Okay?
-Yeah. alright.
Hey. sweet boy. Hey.
Everything's going to be fine.
Don't be afraid.
But you have to promise me
you'll fight. Okay?
Can't someone call an ambulance?
Easy. easy. Are you okay? Don't get up.
I'll call an ambulance.
Kitty?
Oh. man. It hurts so bad.
-Are you faking it or something?
-What are you talking about?
-Dude!
-Alright. alright.
Police.
A guy passing by asked me to do this.
He gave me 1.000 euros.
Fuck!
Nico!
-We have to go in. now!
-Goddamn it.
Caro? What's wrong with his heart rate?
Caro?
Caro? Why is it doing that?
Sam…
NEXT TIME
-We got something?
-I recognized a name.
McCartney wants to make a statement
so no one else tries to fuck with him.
Ten thousand euros.
For what the blind guy has to tell me.
Roman. we have four days left.